Princess Iris, I have already done what needs to be done.
爱丽丝殿下 手续已经办好了
Mr. Kazuma will now be officially considered a guest…
这样就能让和真先生 正式作为客人…
Darkness then
然后
clenched the towel tightly while being completely naked
达克妮丝全裸紧抓着毛巾
and showing a shy face…
露出害羞的表情…
Sh-Showing a shy face?
露…露出害羞的表情
Yeah.
嗯
After she put on a shy face, what happened?
她露出害羞的表情怎么了
Damn!
混蛋
What the heck are you talking about with Princess Iris?
你在跟爱丽丝殿下乱说些什么
Wanna die?
想被我砍吗
Iris asked me to tell the story.
是爱丽丝要求我讲的
How dare you address her by her name?
你凭什么直呼她的名字
Address her as Your Highness.
给我叫她王女殿下
This guy is such a nuisance.
这家伙好麻烦
I allowed Mr. Kazuma
是我跟和真先生说
to call me by my name.
可以直接叫我的名字的
Princess Iris.
爱丽丝殿下…
Instead,
比起这个
what did Lalatina do as she clenched the towel tightly?
拉拉蒂娜紧抓着毛巾做了什么
No way!
不行
It is inappropriate for you to hear about this!
这不是您应该听的话题
Mr. Kazuma,
和真先生
please do not talk about these things with Princess Iris.
请您别再跟爱丽丝殿下讲这类的事
I'm sorry.
对不起
She was very forthcoming at the castle.
她在城堡里倒是很坦率
No choice, then…
没办法 不然…
I will just tell you how I won the deal I made with Darkness,
就讲我和达克妮丝约好
in which the loser had to suffer.
输的人会吃苦头时我赢的事吧
Tell me.
我…我要听
Please tell me.
拜托你跟我说
No way, Princess Iris!
不行 爱丽丝殿下
That man is talking nonsense!
不能听这个男人讲的话
This guy is a total loser!
这个男人是没用的家伙
(Konosuba Season 3)
《为美好的世界献上祝福！ 第三季》
(Episode 3: Re-Educate this Arrogant Girl)
(第3集 为自大的少女进行再次教育)
Then, next…
那接下来
It is the way to handle being sucked up by a gigantic toad.
是被巨型蟾蜍吞下去时的应对方法
-Firstly, what needs to be noted is… -Let me sort out the current situation.
-首先要注意的是… -我整理一下目前的状况
W-Welcome, Mr. Kazuma.
欢…欢迎光临 和真先生
Please make yourself at home here.
请您把这里当作自己家
Have a good rest.
好好休息吧
This is your room, Mr. Kazuma.
这里是和真先生的房间
Ex-Excuse me…
请…请问一下
Lady?
小姐
My name is Rain.
我叫蕾茵
Miss Rain, this is a kidnapping, isn't it?
蕾茵小姐 这是绑架吧
We invited you as a guest,
我们是以客人的身份邀请您
this is not a kidnapping.
并不是绑架
No, this is clearly a kidnapping.
不 这明明是绑架吧
Usually, Princess Iris is very obedient and behaves well,
平常乖巧听话的爱丽丝殿下
but she acted this way.
做出了这样的行为
Please forgive her first rash move
能不能请您原谅她初次任性
and play with her for a while.
暂时当她的玩伴呢
No matter what you say…
就算你这么说…
I'm sorry.
对不起
Lalatina seems to be very happy.
拉拉蒂娜看起来很快乐的样子
I am envious,
我觉得很羡慕
so could you please spend
只要短短的几天就好
a few short days with me as well?
能不能也请你陪我玩呢
That's what Her Highness said.
殿下这么说
She's quite cute, isn't it?
还满可爱的嘛
Alright then.
好吧
Miss Rain.
蕾茵小姐
Tell my friends
请你转告我的伙伴
that I will be staying here for a short time.
说我会暂时住在这里
It sounds fun to have school festivals.
校庆 听起来真好玩
I can't believe it's run by people my age.
居然是由和我同龄的人自己开店
But
不过
-could it really make enough to pay everyone? -It surprised me that she was interested in hearing about school life.
-这样能赚到给大家的薪水吗 -没想到她这么喜欢听学校的事
The princess appears to be very envious
对我来说很无聊的那段日子
of the days that I found extremely dull.
对王女殿下来说却非常羡慕
Why not just open a school if you love it so much?
既然你这么喜欢 干脆创个学校吧
Devil King's Army alert!
魔王军警报
Knights are required to depart immediately!
骑士团立刻出动
-We are in need of the assistance of high-level adventurers. -Again?
-又来了吗 -请高级的冒险者前来支援
That is the case here.
这里的情况就是这样
It is really impossible to concentrate on education.
实在没办法专注在课业上
Indeed,
这么说起来 这个世界
everyone has a hard time in this world
因为魔王那家伙的关系
due to that Devil King.
大家的日子都不好过啊
The Devil King's Army's raids have been thwarted.
魔王军的偷袭已经平定
Adventurers who came to our aid will be rewarded.
我们会付给前来协助的冒险者酬劳
Kindly retrieve it from the guild counter.
请到公会窗口领取
It was the capital of the kingdom, yet it was raided.
明明是王都 居然遭到偷袭
This nation is in utter chaos.
这个国家是怎么回事啊
I really hope that the Japanese people
希望那些拥有作弊能力
who are capable of cheating will help up a little.
从日本来的家伙们振作一点
Thanks for
今天
telling me fun stories today.
谢谢你讲有趣的故事给我听
Please ask Rain to teleport you
明天请蕾茵用转移
back to Axel tomorrow.
送你回阿克塞尔就行了
Because staying here is not very safe.
因为待在这里并不是很安全
That's true.
说得也是
There is nothing I can do to protect this place, even if I stay.
就算我留下来也没办法保护这里
I know those who remained in Axel
虽然发生了很多事
-are concerned about me, -Kazuma.
-但留在阿克塞尔的她们 -和真…
-despite all that has transpired.
-应该也很担心我吧
It makes me a little sad to leave,
尽管有点依依不舍
but I shall go back.
我还是回去吧
Do you mind if I ask you to tell me adventure stories again?
之后还能请你讲冒险故事给我听吗
Of course not.
当然可以
I will come back for you, Iris.
我会为了爱丽丝再来的
I always feel you resemble my older brother.
总觉得你有点像以前的兄长大人
I no longer have casual conversations with my own brother like this.
我现在已经不会和自己的兄长 像这样闲聊了
I really want you to stay,
其实我希望你继续留下来
but I can't be stubborn any longer.
但我不能再耍任性了
What did you just say?
你刚刚说什么
Um…
那个…
I really want you to stay.
其实我希望你继续留下来
No, not this.
不对 不是这一句
What did you say I resembled before that?
在这句之前你说我像什么
Um… You resemble my older brother.
呃…你有点像以前的兄长大人
Could you please say that again?
麻烦你再说一遍
You resemble my older brother.
你有点像兄长大人
Say it again.
再说一遍
If possible, say it more affectionately.
可以的话 请叫得亲密一点
You're a bit like my brother.
你有点像哥哥
I am staying in this castle!
我决定留在这座城堡了
How may I be of assistance, Mr. Kazuma?
您叫我吗 和真先生
I would like a cup of coffee, Sebastian.
赛巴斯钦 给我一杯醒脑的咖啡
My name is Heidel.
我叫海德尔
Please, Heidel.
麻烦你了 海德尔
Um, I'll make the bed.
那个 我来整理床铺
Don't mind me, Mary.
你不用在意我 玛丽
Yes, sir.
是
Good morning.
早安
Brother.
哥哥
This is so nice.
说得好
How sweet that you refer to me as a brother!
哥哥 说得好
Good morning, Iris.
早安 爱丽丝
Please put on your pants.
请你把裤子穿好
(Konosuba) Huh?
啊…
That's not it!
不是的
That's not it, Iris!
不是的 爱丽丝
I'm not a pervert!
哥哥并不是变态
Yeah, yeah.
我知道了啦
Please put on your pants, elder brother.
请你把裤子穿好 兄长大人
Call me brother!
这时候要叫我哥哥
It breaks my heart that you seem to be intentionally putting distance between us!
感觉你故意疏远我 我好难过
Iris!
爱丽丝
Iris no longer calls me brother.
爱丽丝不再叫我哥哥了
After that,
我在这之后
I play tag
陪爱丽丝玩捉迷藏
and hide-and-seek with Iris
陪她玩鬼抓人
and sometimes interrupt her lessons.
然后 偶尔妨碍爱丽丝上课
So, to sum it up, I am her daily playmate.
总之 我每天都在当她的玩伴
I want you to play this game with me today.
我希望你今天陪我玩这个游戏
There is just that she looks
只不过她有时候
worried sometimes.
会露出有所顾虑的样子
Perhaps it is because, as Rain mentioned,
也许是因为她就像蕾茵所说的
she is usually a very well-behaved child.
平常是个很乖巧听话的孩子吧
Iris has to know full well
爱丽丝一定
that her spoiled brat words
很清楚自己说的每一句任性的话
baffle those around her.
都会让身边的人不知道该如何是好
If we play, I will compete seriously,
我不会为了礼让对手就放水
so I will not hold back to be nice to my opponent.
要比就会认真比
Do you still want to play even if that happens?
这样你也要玩吗
Yes.
要
Please take our game very seriously.
我希望你认真跟我玩
Okay, but do not weep if you lose.
好 输了可别哭哦
Since we are going to play seriously,
既然要认真比
we must exchange greetings before the game begins.
游戏之前必须先打招呼
Good game.
请多指教
Um…
那个…
Let's call it a day.
今天就到此为止吧
Are you going to run after you win?
你打算赢了就跑吗
You should do your best if we are competing!
既然要比就要拿出全力吧
Do not hold back simply because you do not want to compete!
你可别因为不想比了就手下留情哦
I can tell even if you try to lose!
就算你故意输掉 我也看得出来
It is awkward to say this because I invited you to play with me,
是我拜托你陪我玩的 这么说有点过意不去
(Konosuba) but you are a real pain to deal with, elder brother!
但兄长大人真是有够难搞
I won!
我赢了
Man. Elder brother, you're just like a child.
真是的 兄长大人简直像个小孩子
Even though you lost, you are still so cocky.
输了还敢这么嚣张
Okay, here is this bamboo dragonfly for you.
好吧 我把这个竹蜻蜓献给你
Thank you.
谢谢
Next time, let us take it outside to play.
下次我们带着它出去玩吧
You should get out more.
你还是多出去走走比较好
In this world,
这个世界上
there may be demons that people find strange
也许有别人觉得与众不同的恶魔
and liches that eat nothing but bread crusts.
还有把吐司边当作主食的巫妖哦
You can't trick me just because I don't go outside very often.
你别以为我没见过世面 就瞧不起我
How could there be such demons and liches?
怎么可能有那种恶魔和巫妖啊
Besides…
而且…
A band of knights will form an escort
如果我出去外面
as soon as I step outside.
骑士团就会作为护卫出动
Konosuba.
为美好的世界献上祝福！
How may I be of assistance, Mr. Kazuma?
您叫我吗 和真先生
I would like a cup of coffee, Sebastian.
赛巴斯钦 给我一杯醒脑的咖啡
My name is Heidel.
我叫海德尔
Please, Heidel.
麻烦你了 海德尔
A week has passed already, huh?
已经过了一周了啊
Alright.
好了
Mary is coming to change the sheets soon.
女仆玛丽差不多要来换床单了
As a noble,
身为一名贵族
how should I stand in her way today?
今天要怎么妨碍她呢
Here she is.
她来了啊
Good morning, Mary.
早安 玛丽
Don't think I'll let you change the sheets that easily.
别以为我会这么简单就让你换床单
Say this quickly if you want to
好了 如果你想快点换好床单
change the sheets:
就这么说
"Master, please."
主人 拜托您
"Could you please let me help you…"
请让小的帮主人…
Please let me help you what?
主人 请您怎样?
Tell me, Kazuma.
说啊 和真
Just say it out loud so everyone can hear
来 让在场的所有人听听看
what you have to say next.
你接下来要说什么
M-Master, could you please let me
主…主人 请让小的
help you change the sheets that smell…
把沾有主人味道的床单…
Yeah, keep going.
把沾有味道的床单怎么样
What's the matter? Doesn't sexual harassment come naturally to you?
怎么了 你不是很擅长性骚扰吗
Stop being coy and tell me.
别害羞了 快给我说
F-Forgive me.
原…原谅我
Why are you guys here?
为什么你们会在这啊
We've come to take you back.
我们是来带你回去的
Megumin can't sleep at night.
惠惠晚上都睡不着觉
She's been worried about you.
一直在担心你耶
Th-That was a coincidence.
那…那是巧合啦
Don't get confused over such silly things.
不要有这种奇怪的误会
It is my job to play with Iris!
我的职位是爱丽丝的玩伴
Do not get in the way of my peaceful life!
别妨碍我过安稳的生活
That job does not exist in this country, you idiot.
笨蛋 这个国家才没这种职位
Kazuma, you are having too much fun by yourself.
和真你自己一个人快活太奸诈了
We all took out the leaders of the Devil King's Army.
魔王军的干部是大家一起打倒的
If I don't get to live in the castle too, it is just unfair.
我也要在城堡生活 不然太不公平了
Aqua, shut up!
阿库娅闭嘴啦
You are only going to make things worse.
你会把事情搞得更复杂
Um…
那个…
Princess Iris.
爱丽丝殿下
I'm sorry.
对不起
I overheard your conversation.
我听到你们的对话了
Despite being a hopeless case,
虽然他是无药可救的人
he is a famous adventurer in Axel.
但在阿克塞尔也是有名的冒险者
The people in that city care about him,
那个城市里有他的朋友
and he has friends there.
还有担心他的伙伴
We also worry about him.
我们也是
Could you please let him go?
能不能请您放他离开呢
Iris, tell her quickly.
爱丽丝 快告诉她
"Brother is going to live in the castle with me and play with me."
哥哥要在城堡和我玩耍过生活
You're right.
说得也是
Sorry. I acted solely in my self-interest.
对不起 我说了任性的话
It's okay!
可以的
It's okay to do that, Iris!
可以的 爱丽丝
You are the highest-ranking person in the castle!
你是这座城堡地位最高的人
Tell her, quickly!
快告诉她 快啊
Hurry up!
快啊
Lalatina.
拉拉蒂娜
Please let me host a dinner
今天一晚就好
for him tonight to say goodbye.
我能帮他举行送别的晚宴吗
Konosuba.
为美好的世界献上祝福！
Look, Kazuma.
你看 和真
This is really yummy.
这个超好吃的
Natural wild melon with prosciutto!
是天然的野哈密瓜配生火腿
It's still alive!
还活跳跳的哦
This tastes great too.
这个也很好吃哦
It is pudding on vinegar rice with mustard soy sauce on top!
在醋饭上放布丁 再淋上芥末酱油
Yeah, yeah. Great.
是是 真是太好了
The pudding in my mouth…
布丁在嘴里…
You look lovely today, too.
您今天也好美
The moonlight blossom,
跟您的美貌相比
which only appears once every hundred years, can't hold a candle to your beauty.
连百年只开一次的月光华草 都黯淡无光
I agree.
是啊
You flatter me.
你们过奖了
Oh, right.
对了
Lady Dustiness, do you have a fiancé?
达斯堤尼斯大人有未婚夫了吗
If you don't have one yet…
如果您还没有…
What are you talking about?
你在说什么
Since I always go on blind dates with her, I should be her fiancé!
这应该由一直提出相亲的我先来吧
She has a lot of fans.
真受欢迎
What an impropriety!
真不合体统
I suppose Lady Dustiness should have a better match.
达斯堤尼斯大人 应该有更适合的对象吧
Lord Aldarp.
阿尔达普大人
Hey, what are you doing here?
大叔 你怎么会在这里
Shut up!
闭嘴
My house is still under reconstruction
都怪你把毁灭者的核心
because you sent the Destroyer
传送到我的宅里
to my mansion!
害我直到现在都还在重建
So,
话说回来
who would be a better match for Lady Dustiness?
适合达斯堤尼斯大人的人是谁
Are you still after Darkness, old man?
你还在打达克妮丝的主意吗 大叔
Call me Lord Aldarp.
叫我阿尔达普大人
As it stands, only one person
配得上现在的达斯堤尼斯大人的人
can truly complement Lady Dustiness.
只有一个吧
That is the first prince, Prince Jatice, who is in charge of the regular army
就是现在正率领正规军 和魔王军战斗的
fighting the Devil King's Army right now.
第一王子杰帝斯殿下
Prince Jatice, who is the national hero,
国家英雄杰帝斯殿下
and Lady Dustiness, who just beat the leaders of the Devil King's army,
和近来年打败魔王军干部的 达斯堤尼斯大人
are a great match.
没有人比他们更速配
Th-That makes sense.
有…有道理
A more outstanding match than Prince Jatice…
比第一王子杰帝斯殿下 更出色的对象…
Hey.
喂
What about your shitty relationship with me?
你和我之间糜烂的关系要怎么办
What the hell, Lalatina?
搞什么啊 拉拉蒂娜
Do you want to abandon me?
你想抛弃我吗
Wh-What made you say that out of the blue?
你…你干嘛突然这么说
What about all the sweet times we had?
我们度过的甜蜜时光呢
Not too long ago, you still called me master…
不久前你还叫我主人…
Pranks can get out of hand if they go too far.
恶作剧过头的话会一发不可收拾的
Are you sure of this, Lalatina?
这样好吗 拉拉蒂娜
People who want to date you will run away
如果对我使用你天生的怪力
if you use your natural super-strength on me.
追求者会吓跑哦
Gosh.
真是的
(Konosuba) You are still a great actor, as usual.
你的演技还是一样好呢
I am just a little naughty.
我只有一点点坏心眼
But when I see Darkness's worried face,
但是看到达克妮丝露出困扰的表情
I say strange things without realizing it.
就不自觉说出奇怪的话
After all, isn't this my farewell party?
因为这不是我的送别会吗
Why are they ignoring the protagonist?
他们凭什么丢下主角不管
They are having a great time over there.
自己在那边开心啊
The protagonist is obviously right here.
主角明明在这里耶
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么
Iris!
爱丽丝
As expected of Iris!
不愧是爱丽丝
It is too much to handle being alone at this party.
在这种宴会上独自一个人 实在是太难熬了
Iris, you really are a good sister.
爱丽丝果然是个好妹妹
A-Am I?
哪…哪有
Next, a huge toad
那么 接下来从这个玻璃杯里
comes out of this glass.
竟然冒出巨型蟾蜍
Her passion as a performer is rising again.
她的艺人热血又沸腾了啊
Look.
看啊
What do you think? This is…
怎么样 这就是…
This castle will return to its usual serene state beginning tomorrow.
明天后这座城堡又会变安静了呢
Because the person who irritates Claire
因为惹克莱儿生气
and causes Rain trouble is leaving.
让蕾茵伤脑筋的某个人要回去了
Is not that good?
这不是很好吗
That being said, what about someone like me do you like?
不过我这种人的哪一点 讨你喜欢了啊
I have never met anyone like you before.
我第一次遇到你这样的人
Everyone loves and cherishes you,
受到大家的爱护
and you are brave,
什么都不怕
rude, and outspoken.
没礼貌又直言不讳
You teach me strange things,
教我这个王族奇怪的事
and you are utterly obsessed with beating me, like a child.
还幼稚地认真想赢过我
Hey.
喂
I'm not asking what you dislike about me,
我不是在问你讨厌我什么地方
I'm asking what you like about me.
是在问你喜欢我什么地方
Yeah, I'm telling you the reasons I like you.
嗯 我正在说喜欢你的理由哦
Quite cute, huh?
挺可爱的嘛
The time I spent with you
和你度过的这段时光
is something I will never forget.
对我来说一定很难忘
I am so envious of Lalatina.
我好羡慕拉拉蒂娜
I bet you guys are happy all the time.
你们一定每天都很开心吧
Tomorrow,
到了明天
she will definitely go back to being a princess and keep herself in check,
她一定又会恢复王族的身份 压抑自己
living her life as a good child who does what she is told.
扮演乖巧听话的好孩子生活吧
Is it really impossible for me to stay in this castle?
我真的没办法留在这座城堡吗
I wish I could also be an adventurer.
真希望我也能当冒险者
Do you know?
你知道吗
It has been passed down through generations that the royal family has very strong magical skills and abilities.
王族代代都拥有 很高的魔力和素养哦
It is unlikely that I will be able to become a cross knight like Lalatina,
虽然我应该无法成为 像拉拉蒂娜那样的十字骑士
but I could be a priest or a magician instead.
但是当魔法师或祭司也不错吧
I am going to become an adventurer that will surprise even you.
我一定能成为连兄长大人 都大吃一惊的冒险者
Alternately, I could become a well-known,
或是从事盗贼行业
chivalrous thief who is infamous in the city's back alleys and streets.
成为红遍街头巷尾的义贼 好像也不错
But I am afraid calling out my desire to become a chivalrous thief
不过 如果我说要当义贼
might enrage Claire all over again.
会不会又惹克莱儿生气呢
What did you just say?
你刚刚说什么
Chivalrous thief?
你是说义贼吗
I have heard that there are thieves target nobles with bad reputations,
我听说有盗贼 专门挑风评很差的贵族下手
and that after the crime,
然后案发过后
a substantial donation is always left in front
艾莉丝教团的孤儿院门前
of the Eris Church orphanage.
都会留下大笔的捐款
E-Elder brother?
兄…兄长大人
This is it!
就是这个
-Please have a friendly match with me one day. -Darkness!
-请您有机会和我较量一下 -达克妮丝
Darkness!
达克妮丝
Claire, you are here as well.
克莱儿也来得正好
I-Is there something wrong?
有…有什么事
I've heard.
我听说了
There is a chivalrous thief in the royal capital who only targets nobles, right?
现在王都有专挑贵族下手的义贼吧
Y-Yeah.
没…没错
It appears that all targeted nobles are corrupt.
被盯上的好像都是品行不好的贵族
I'll help you catch that chivalrous thief.
我来帮你们抓那个义贼
What?
什么
He actually stated that he will apprehend
居然说要抓到现在为止
the thief who has left no clues thus far.
都没掌握任何线索的那个盗贼
What is that nasty man talking about?
那个寒酸的男人在说什么啊
Despite being ordinary,
虽然不起眼
-You nobles, I heard everything. -it looks like he is a friend of Lord Dustiness.
-各位贵族 我都听到了哦 -但他好像是达斯堤尼斯卿的伙伴
-He is?
-他吗
Though he is known as a chivalrous thief, theft is still theft.
虽说是义贼 但窃盗就是窃盗
We must not ignore him.
绝对不能放过他
Why would someone who doesn't care about justice say that?
与正义感无缘的你为何这么说
I will stay to keep everyone safe.
为了保护大家 我要留下来
You really are…
你这个人真是…
Amazing!
太棒了
Truly worthy of being Lady Dustiness' companion.
不愧是达斯堤尼斯大人的伙伴
Don't misunderstand.
别误会
There was no way that the chivalrous thief could target me, of course.
我当然不可能成为义贼的目标
I am not guilty of anything, too.
我也没做过亏心事
Of course, I do not think I would be targeted either.
当然 也不觉得自己会被盯上
They are really simple to grasp.
这些家伙还真是好懂
Is that so? Is that so?
是吗是吗
Want to see your favorite brother show off his skills?
你就这么想看最喜欢的兄长大人 大显身手吗
Leave it to me.
包在我身上
I am going to keep hanging out in the castle and do nothing.
我就继续在城堡游手好闲
He will be caught soon enough.
不久之后一定会抓到他的
I have high hopes for you, ordinary man.
我很看好你哦 不起眼的男人
You are more capable than I expected.
你比我想象得还要能干
Quickly apprehend him and alleviate our concerns.
快点抓到他 让我们放心吧
What? What?
什么什么
Can we have delicious food here tomorrow too?
明天也能在这里吃美味的料理吗
Okay, okay.
好啊 好啊
Why do not we just eat till we are 80% full today
为了留点胃口到明天
to make room for tomorrow?
今天就吃八分饱吧
What nonsense are you two talking about?
你们两个在胡说什么啊
Alright then.
我明白了
Mr. Kazuma, you should go to the house of the noble who agrees with this idea
和真先生 就住进赞成这个建议的贵族家里
and wait for the thief there.
在家里埋伏吧
Everyone should try their utmost to aid Mr. Kazuma.
大家也要尽全力协助和真先生
That's not it!
不是的
It's not like that!
不是这样啦
(Episode 4: Divine Punishment for This Handsome Chivalrous Thief)
(第4集 为帅气的 义贼献上天谴)
They touched!
碰到了啊
Long time no see, Devil King.
好久不见 魔王大人
I am your faithful servant,
我是您忠实的仆人
Growth Chimera--
成长型奇美拉席…